EMMA PERSINGER

Program Evaluation Data Analyst with 2 years experience using analytical and interpersonal skills to support and improve Kansas Medicaid and Behavioral Health programs. Has applied a passion for process improvement and development to increase the efficiency of 9+ quarterly/annual tasks, including the development of 3 sample pulls, updating of 2 data crosswalks, and condensing of over 27,000+ lines of outdated SQL code from 16 queries into 2 queries with under 1000 lines of code.

Boulder, CO 80303

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

KS Dept. for Aging and Disability Services — *Data Analyst*

August 2020 - Present

Program Evaluation Data Analyst specializing in Behavioral Health, responsible for a variety of federal Medicaid and SAMHSA reporting and internal/external data requests. Frequently advises internal stakeholders to enhance data-driven decision making, including the development of new reports and metrics as well as updating outdated systems and reports. Uses Microsoft Excel, Word, Access, and SQL daily, with additional familiarity in Business Objects and Power BI.

EDUCATION

Emporia State University, Emporia, KS — MS Informatics, Concentration in Quantitative Economics

June 2021 – Present

Degree in progress, with course experience in areas such as Econometrics, Programming & Data Analysis, and Database Management, as well as overarching application of programming using R for statistical analysis. Graduation set for December 2023.

Emporia State University, Emporia, KS — BS Quantitative Economics, Minors in Political Science and Ethnic & Gender Studies, with honors

August 2018 - August 2020

 $4.0~{
m GPA}$, Class Rank: 1, honors designation is met by Honors College leadership and community engagement requirements.

LEADERSHIP ROLES

Emporia State Young Democrats — *President*

January 2019 – August 2020

Lyon County Democratic Precinct Committee — *Precinct 2 Committeewoman*

November 2018 – 2020

Working with Democratic party members to campaign for local and state candidates. Communicating effectively with people from many backgrounds and ideologies.

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Emporia State Residential Life — Student Office Assistant

March 2019 - May 2020

Assisting professional office staff on any projects or daily tasks, such as communicating with students/parents, running housing events, editing marketing material, etc.

Emporia High School USD 253 — Assistant Debate Coach

August 2018 – January 2019

Serving in a mentoring role to students in learning about a variety of real-world debate topics, communicating persuasively, research methods, etc. utilizing four years of accomplished debate/forensics experience.

Dunkin' Donuts — Crew Member

May 2019 - January 2020

SKILLS

Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Access, Powerpoint)
SQL (SSMS)

R

SAP Business Objects
Public Speaking/Interpersonal
Communication
Written Communication

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Emerging Leaders Academy -University of Kansas Public Management Academy

Attendee, February – June 2020

ADvancing States' Home and Community-Based Services (HCBS) Conference

Attendee, December 2020

Emporia State Honors College

Member, Aug. 2018 - Aug. 2020

Leadership training/events and work on adaptive challenges outside the classroom.

SERVICE

Topeka March for Our Lives *Invited Speaker*, March 2018

ALA Sunflower Girls State *Volunteer*, Summers 2018/19

Unite for Reproductive and Gender Equality

Member, Aug. 2019 - Aug. 2020

Universities Fighting World Hunger: Food for Students Volunteer, 2018 - 2020

HONORS

Summa Cum Laude

Dean's List for College of Liberal Arts and Sciences (all semesters)

References available upon request